### Contact

+201023034581 (Mobile) terminatorbds8090@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedsaad-35891816b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
Microsoft Office
Management
Microsoft Excel

# **Ahmed Saad**

Junior Software Engineer Egypt

### Summary

I always loved computers and anything tech-related ever since I was little. After I finished high school and it was time to start college my dad decided that Mechatronics Engineering is an excellent major and the job market is in high demand. After finishing my preparatory year I fell in love with my programming course and I decided to switch majors to study Computer Engineering. Today, I am in Junior year and I never regretted my decision and never will.

During college, I Participated in US Embassy Hackathon and was placed 4th among 50

teams. Developed a number of software programs with high success levels. Finished a 2 weeks

software development internship. Solved more than 50 programming problems on code forces and I absolutely love the dopamine rush of getting the Green accepted status.

The Digital/Computer industry is the future for the next decades and I am proud every day of the "Software Engineer" title.

## Experience

Homes for the Homeless 3 months

Assistant Director of Programming August 2019 - August 2019 (1 month) Greater New York City Area

- Supervisor of Lifeguards including waterfront director and all activity specialsts
- Managed the behavioral challenges of a wide variety of children with Autism and Mental Health challenges caused by environment and low socioeconomic status.

- Maintained a daily detailed schedule which consisted of multiple activities for 3 sessions, 2 weeks at a time. Organized daily activities and evening programs with senior staff.
- Responsible to create a schedule for the camp staff to follow, and coordinate with my staff members to add different activities to the schedule.
- Responsible to assist the camp director in any matter that comes up and was the first person in charge when the camp director is not available.

#### Unit Leader

June 2019 - August 2019 (3 months)

New York, United States

#### appenza

Intern

September 2018 - September 2018 (1 month)

Cairo, Egypt

Micro Internship

Homes for the Homeless General Counselor June 2017 - August 2018 (1 year 3 months) Central Valley, New York, United States

### Education

Arab Academy for Science, Technology and Maritime Transport Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering (2016 - 2021)